hello and welcome to the 25th tutorial
on how to program a g-script 2.
so in this tutorial i'm going to show
you a new command call called
trigger server
if you remember in the 23rd tutorial i
explained
sort of how to use trigger action and
how it only how it works for
level npcs
and what it does is it makes it so you
can go from client side to server side
in the same and be in the same script
well trigger server does the same thing
except you use it for things like
database npcs which are like npcs that
are
permanently on the server not like level
npcs
and or weapons or classes which i
haven't
which i don't use but here's a weapon
it's called
trigger
and i already added it to myself and
let's start it
on
weapon fired
what if you remember what on weapon fire
does is
if you press d with the weapon selected
from your
inventory
then it'll run whatever is in these
brackets
okay let's add the code trigger
server this is the command that will
do what i said
guist.name
no
okay so here is the command
trigger server
the first parameter
is
i put quotes gui
what this does is i'm not entirely sure
actually
when you take it out then it doesn't
work and what i don't know what else you
could replace it with
but anyway you can just leave it as gui
i don't even know if you can change
anything
the second parameter i put this.name
this.name is the variable of the
weapon's name you can replace this with
any weapon name you want and it'll
trigger server to that weapon like if
any other weapon has
a function on
actually i'll explain that in a second
the third parameter is null you can
replace it with just nothing but null
what after here what happens is if you
want to have any variables that can send
over then you can do that
okay let's go back to server side and
put function
on action
server side
okay what this command does is if you
have a trigger server in client side
it's going to make it go to this
function
and it runs right over in these brackets
okay let's put
for
temp dot
dot
pl and all players so it's going to loop
through all the players using the pl
variable
then we can do something like pl dot
hearts is equal to zero
so it's going to loop through everyone
on the server and it's going to make
their hearts which is their health equal
to zero
and that's going to kill them instantly
so if you ever wanted a weapon that
kills everyone on the server which i
don't know why you would
it would do that okay let's save this
i'm going to select it i already have it
press d
and it kills me including and
my test player
okay
so if we go back to the script we'll see
that it worked
and yeah if let's say we want to
avoid us killing ourselves but kill
everyone else
then what we want to do
is
put if
player dot
no if pl dot account is equal to my
account name which is brawl 755284
then it's going to make
the hearts equal to zero
i mean everyone except me
oh wait
that's just going to make me i want to
put not equal to i'm sorry
okay apply
press d and it kills everyone but me
we can do some other things too
with this
let's say we want to make everybody say
something on the server
oh
i mess that up a bit
okay what we would do
is put pl dot
um
chat is equal to
hi
so now everyone on the server is going
to say hi
oops
hi
we can also i can show you how to send
variables over what we do is go here to
null and we'll put a variable that we
want like temp dot
let's put
no
okay let's do this
player
actually i'm going to change the
function to on
player chats
so as soon as i say something it's going
to go to server side
okay i'm going to put
temp dot pl no not pl p
is equal to player dot chat
that would go here is go here
and put temp dot
p
then here on server side we put uh what
we want to change the name to just keep
sp
temp dot p
and here
instead of saying hi we're going to say
temp dot p
so we're saying something temp.p is
getting set as our chat then it's going
to send that variable over to here
and it's going to
everyone on the server is going to say
that
everything i say so i'm going to say
hi
and the test person says it say q
so anyway everyone's just going to say
what you say
so let's say we want to make a summoning
script we can do that with this let's
change this back to null
and get rid of this code here
and then we're going to put if
player dot
chat is equal to
uh
summon all
so if we're going to say something and
then our chat is equal to the exact
words seminal it's going to run trigger
server and go to server side
so now what we want to do is here we're
looping through everyone i'm going to
put a command
called
uh
set level 2 so we're going to put pl dot
set level two here we're specifying
who the set level is going to happen to
it's going to happen to the
all the players
and then we're going to put
parentheses
player player.name
comma
player.x comma player.y
the first parameter is the level we want
them to warp to we can replace it with
anything like
new
or new seven dot
i think this is our current level i mean
new nine is our current level
and then we can make it so they warp to
our player x and player y we can also
make them warp to anything else like
let's say
ten
10. and if we run this
and i say summon all
everyone's going to be warped to this
level and at 10 coordinates
but we don't want that we want them to
warp to us so we're going to put
which is our level
player.x which is our x-axis coordinate
and player.y which is our y-axis
coordinate
we save this
i want to say sum and all
everybody on the server warps to me
which can be pretty useful as a staff
tool in case you want to warp everyone
and show someone something or just for
testing
so anyway that's the
end of this tutorial and i'm glad and i
hope you understand how to use
trigger server now
and how to use set level 2.
anyway
bye